export const data = [

    {
        Question: "What is React.js mainly used for?",
        Option1: "Server-side scripting",
        Option2: "Building user interfaces",
        Option3: "Database management",
        Option4: "Server-side scripting",
        ans: 2,
    },

    {
        Question: "Who is considered the unifier of modern Nepal and the founder of the Shah dynasty?",
        Option1: "King Prithvi Narayan Shah",
        Option2: "King Tribhuvan",
        Option3: "King Gyanendra",
        Option4: "King Birendra",
        ans: 1,
    },
    {
        Question: "In React, what is JSX?",
        Option1: "JavaScript Extension",
        Option2: " XML syntax for JavaScript",
        Option3: "Java and XML",
        Option4: "JavaScript Expressions",
        ans: 2,
    },
    {
        Question: "How can you pass data from a parent component to a child component in React?",
        Option1: "Using state",
        Option2: "Using props",
        Option3: "Using refs",
        Option4: "Using context",
        ans: 2,
    },
    {
        Question: "What is the purpose of the useEffect hook in React?",
        Option1: "Handling form submissions",
        Option2: "Performing side effects in functional components",
        Option3: "Managing component state",
        Option4: "Defining event listeners",
        ans: 2,
    },
    {
        Question: "Which of the following is not a valid way to declare a variable in JavaScript?",
        Option1: "let",
        Option2: "const",
        Option3: "Var",
        Option4: "declare",
        ans: 4,
    },
    {
        Question: "What is the virtual DOM in React used for?",
        Option1: " Improving server performance",
        Option2: "Improving database queries",
        Option3: "Optimizing rendering efficiency",
        Option4: "Enhancing network communication",
        ans: 3,
    },
    {
        Question: "How do you conditionally render content in React?",
        Option1: " Using if-else statements",
        Option2: " Using the ternary operator",
        Option3: "Using switch statements",
        Option4: " All of the above",
        ans: 4,
    },
    {
        Question: "What is the purpose of the useState hook in React?",
        Option1: "Fetching data from an API",
        Option2: "Managing component state in functional components",
        Option3: "Handling form submissions",
        Option4: "Defining event listeners",
        ans: 2,

    },
    {
        Question: "Which method is used to perform a side effect in a functional component only once when the component mounts?",
        Option1: " useEffect",
        Option2: "componentDidMount",
        Option3: "useLayoutEffect",
        Option4: " componentWillMount",
        ans: 2,
    },
    {
        Question: "What is your computer teacher name?",
        Option1: " sajan",
        Option2: "ram",
        Option3: "Anil",
        Option4: "Nitesh",
        ans: 4,
    },
]